<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>My life on Portfolio website for Mengting(Julia) Zhu</title>
    <link>/blogs/</link>
    <description>Recent content in My life on Portfolio website for Mengting(Julia) Zhu</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 31 Oct 2017 22:27:21 -0500</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/blogs/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Graduation from Fudan University</title>
      <link>/blogs/blog1/blog1/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 27 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blogs/blog1/blog1/</guid>
      <description>Today is my graduation day! I haven’t been on campus for almost 6 months due to the COVID-19, and I had to communicate with my mentor online. Also I finished my graduation thesis on how the timeliness and accuracy of the first pre-announcement published by listed companies affects the stock price crash risk during this period.
I really enjoy my time studying here. This is the picture I took in front my favorite building on campus before I left.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Exchange @ Schulich School of Business </title>
      <link>/blogs/blog2/blog2/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 31 Oct 2017 22:26:09 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blogs/blog2/blog2/</guid>
      <description>I had an exchange experience studying in Schulich School of Business in Toronto, Canada. During the exchange term, I applied 2 different investment strategies in the US stock market and completed the group investment project using Stocktrak, a platform for virtual investment. And I got to know many good friends in this process.
Apart from studying, I also visited many places in Canada, such as the Niagara Falls, and Yellowknife.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>I Love Ultimate Frisbee!</title>
      <link>/blogs/blog3/blog3/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 31 Oct 2017 21:28:43 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blogs/blog3/blog3/</guid>
      <description>Ultimate Frisbee combines all the best elements of American football, soccer, basketball, and everyone’s favorite beach sport: tossing a Frisbee disc. But a good game of Ultimate Frisbee is fast-paced, intense and strategic.
I started to play this sports when I was in high school, and it has been 7 years since then. I met some of my best friends through this process, and I will continue playing it as well.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
