<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Portfolio website for Mengting(Julia) Zhu</title>
    <link>/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Portfolio website for Mengting(Julia) Zhu</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 08 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Yield Curve Inversion</title>
      <link>/projects/project1/homework3-q4/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/projects/project1/homework3-q4/</guid>
      <description>Every so often, we hear warnings from commentators on the “inverted yield curve” and its predictive power with respect to recessions. An explainer what a inverted yield curve is can be found here. If you’d rather listen to something, here is a great podcast from NPR on yield curve indicators
In addition, many articles and commentators think that, e.g., Yield curve inversion is viewed as a harbinger of recession. One can always doubt whether inversions are truly a harbinger of recessions, and use the attached parable on yield curve inversions.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Youth Risk Behavior Surveillance</title>
      <link>/projects/project5/pj5/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/projects/project5/pj5/</guid>
      <description>Every two years, the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention conduct the Youth Risk Behavior Surveillance System (YRBSS) survey, where it takes data from high schoolers (9th through 12th grade), to analyze health patterns. We will work with a selected group of variables from a random sample of observations during one of the years the YRBSS was conducted.
Load the datadata(yrbss)glimpse(yrbss)## Rows: 13,583## Columns: 13## $ age &amp;lt;int&amp;gt; 14, 14, 15, 15, 15, 15, 15, 14, 15, 15, 15.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Excess Rentals in TfL Bike Sharing</title>
      <link>/projects/project3/bikes/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 03 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/projects/project3/bikes/</guid>
      <description>In this case, we are going to take a look at the excess rentals in TfL bike sharing.
Recall the TfL data on how many bikes were hired every single day. We can get the latest data by running the following
url &amp;lt;- &amp;quot;https://data.london.gov.uk/download/number-bicycle-hires/ac29363e-e0cb-47cc-a97a-e216d900a6b0/tfl-daily-cycle-hires.xlsx&amp;quot;# Download TFL data to temporary filehttr::GET(url, write_disk(bike.temp &amp;lt;- tempfile(fileext = &amp;quot;.xlsx&amp;quot;)))## Response [https://airdrive-secure.s3-eu-west-1.amazonaws.com/london/dataset/number-bicycle-hires/2020-09-18T09%3A06%3A54/tfl-daily-cycle-hires.xlsx?X-Amz-Algorithm=AWS4-HMAC-SHA256&amp;amp;X-Amz-Credential=AKIAJJDIMAIVZJDICKHA%2F20201020%2Feu-west-1%2Fs3%2Faws4_request&amp;amp;X-Amz-Date=20201020T092140Z&amp;amp;X-Amz-Expires=300&amp;amp;X-Amz-Signature=540743054f661a81c8a6f0d9351ec6eb1b806bced8ae9527f86a2f02ae63eafd&amp;amp;X-Amz-SignedHeaders=host]## Date: 2020-10-20 09:21## Status: 200## Content-Type: application/vnd.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Country Comparison: Life Expectancy</title>
      <link>/projects/project2/gapminder-assignment/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/projects/project2/gapminder-assignment/</guid>
      <description>gapminder dataset has data on life expectancy, population, and GDP per capita for 142 countries from 1952 to 2007.
Before the analysis, here’s a glipmse of the dataframe and the first 20 rows of data.
glimpse(gapminder)## Rows: 1,704## Columns: 6## $ country &amp;lt;fct&amp;gt; Afghanistan, Afghanistan, Afghanistan, Afghanistan, Afgha...## $ continent &amp;lt;fct&amp;gt; Asia, Asia, Asia, Asia, Asia, Asia, Asia, Asia, Asia, Asi...## $ year &amp;lt;int&amp;gt; 1952, 1957, 1962, 1967, 1972, 1977, 1982, 1987, 1992, 199.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>IBM HR Analytics</title>
      <link>/projects/project4/ibm-hr/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 27 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/projects/project4/ibm-hr/</guid>
      <description>In this case, we will analyze a data set on Human Resource Analytics. The IBM HR Analytics Employee Attrition &amp;amp; Performance data set is a fictional data set created by IBM data scientists.
knitr::opts_chunk$set(message = FALSE, warning = FALSE, tidy=FALSE, # display code as typedsize=&amp;quot;small&amp;quot;) # slightly smaller font for codeoptions(digits = 3)# default figure sizeknitr::opts_chunk$set(fig.width=6.75, fig.height=6.75,fig.align = &amp;quot;center&amp;quot;)library(tidyverse) # Load ggplot2, dplyr, and all the other tidyverse packageslibrary(mosaic)library(ggthemes)library(lubridate)library(fivethirtyeight)library(here)library(skimr)library(janitor)library(vroom)library(tidyquant)library(rvest) # scrape websiteslibrary(purrr) library(lubridate) #to handle dateslibrary(kableExtra)First let us load the data.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About me</title>
      <link>/projects/project0/short-biography/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/projects/project0/short-biography/</guid>
      <description>Mengting(Julia) ZhuI graduated from Fudan University in China, and I am now Reading for Masters of Financial Analysis at London Business School. Apart from school work and activities, I had internship experience in both buy-side and sell-side research.
LanguagesChinese MandarinEnglishSkills &amp;amp; InterestsSAC Certificate of SecuritiesHobbies: Ultimate Frisbee, Singing, Chinese Calligraphy and JoggingContactE-mail:jzhu.mfa2021@london.edu/zmtjulia@outlook.comLinkedIn:https://www.linkedin.com/in/mengting-julia-zhu-a7160b187</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Graduation from Fudan University</title>
      <link>/blogs/blog1/blog1/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 27 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blogs/blog1/blog1/</guid>
      <description>Today is my graduation day! I haven’t been on campus for almost 6 months due to the COVID-19, and I had to communicate with my mentor online. Also I finished my graduation thesis on how the timeliness and accuracy of the first pre-announcement published by listed companies affects the stock price crash risk during this period.
I really enjoy my time studying here. This is the picture I took in front my favorite building on campus before I left.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Exchange @ Schulich School of Business </title>
      <link>/blogs/blog2/blog2/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 31 Oct 2017 22:26:09 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blogs/blog2/blog2/</guid>
      <description>I had an exchange experience studying in Schulich School of Business in Toronto, Canada. During the exchange term, I applied 2 different investment strategies in the US stock market and completed the group investment project using Stocktrak, a platform for virtual investment. And I got to know many good friends in this process.
Apart from studying, I also visited many places in Canada, such as the Niagara Falls, and Yellowknife.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>I Love Ultimate Frisbee!</title>
      <link>/blogs/blog3/blog3/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 31 Oct 2017 21:28:43 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blogs/blog3/blog3/</guid>
      <description>Ultimate Frisbee combines all the best elements of American football, soccer, basketball, and everyone’s favorite beach sport: tossing a Frisbee disc. But a good game of Ultimate Frisbee is fast-paced, intense and strategic.
I started to play this sports when I was in high school, and it has been 7 years since then. I met some of my best friends through this process, and I will continue playing it as well.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hello R Markdown</title>
      <link>/post/2015-07-23-r-rmarkdown/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Jul 2015 21:13:14 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2015-07-23-r-rmarkdown/</guid>
      <description>R MarkdownThis is an R Markdown document. Markdown is a simple formatting syntax for authoring HTML, PDF, and MS Word documents. For more details on using R Markdown see http://rmarkdown.rstudio.com.
You can embed an R code chunk like this:
summary(cars)## speed dist ## Min. : 4.0 Min. : 2.00 ## 1st Qu.:12.0 1st Qu.: 26.00 ## Median :15.0 Median : 36.00 ## Mean :15.4 Mean : 42.98 ## 3rd Qu.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
